<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Posts on Hello</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Posts on Hello</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 03 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        
        <item>
            <title>Phones and Modern Tech Are Needlessly Evil</title>
            <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2025/08/phones-and-modern-tech-are-needlessly-evil/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 03 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2025/08/phones-and-modern-tech-are-needlessly-evil/</guid>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;Everyone carries a phone these days. It connects us, entertains us, and helps us work. On the surface, it feels like a miracle tool. But the truth underneath is darker. Phones and modern technology are not just harmful, they are &lt;em&gt;needlessly&lt;/em&gt; harmful. The way the industry works ensures waste, exploitation, and manipulation. None of it is inevitable. It happens because it makes money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-human-cost-of-materials&#34;&gt;The Human Cost of Materials&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every phone starts with raw materials like cobalt, lithium, and rare earth elements. These resources don’t come free. Many are mined in places where conflict, child labor, and human rights abuses are widespread. In the Democratic Republic of the Congo, industrial cobalt and copper mining has led to forced evictions, unsafe conditions, and severe abuses of human rights. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amnesty.org/en/latest/news/2023/09/drc-cobalt-and-copper-mining-for-batteries-leading-to-human-rights-abuses/&#34;&gt;Amnesty International reports&lt;/a&gt; detail how entire communities are displaced and rights violated.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Everyone carries a phone these days. It connects us, entertains us, and helps us work. On the surface, it feels like a miracle tool. But the truth underneath is darker. Phones and modern technology are not just harmful, they are <em>needlessly</em> harmful. The way the industry works ensures waste, exploitation, and manipulation. None of it is inevitable. It happens because it makes money.</p>
<h2 id="the-human-cost-of-materials">The Human Cost of Materials</h2>
<p>Every phone starts with raw materials like cobalt, lithium, and rare earth elements. These resources don’t come free. Many are mined in places where conflict, child labor, and human rights abuses are widespread. In the Democratic Republic of the Congo, industrial cobalt and copper mining has led to forced evictions, unsafe conditions, and severe abuses of human rights. <a href="https://www.amnesty.org/en/latest/news/2023/09/drc-cobalt-and-copper-mining-for-batteries-leading-to-human-rights-abuses/">Amnesty International reports</a> detail how entire communities are displaced and rights violated.</p>
<p>Government and NGO studies also document forced labor and child labor in cobalt extraction. The U.S. Department of Labor calls cobalt mining in the DRC an area of “forced labor” risk. <a href="https://www.dol.gov/sites/dolgov/files/ILAB/DRC-FL-Cobalt-Report-508.pdf">Forced Labor in Cobalt Mining in the Democratic Republic of the Congo</a> shows that many miners work under dangerous conditions with little protection.</p>
<p>When you add the churn of yearly upgrades, demand fuels these extractive systems. The human cost is hidden from most users, but it is real and measurable.</p>
<h2 id="the-consumerist-machine">The Consumerist Machine</h2>
<p>The suffering does not stop at the mine. Phones are designed to keep us replacing, wasting, and consuming.</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Planned obsolescence</strong>: Software updates often slow older phones so they feel sluggish or incompatible with new apps.</li>
<li><strong>Marginal improvements</strong>: Producers hype small gains in speed or cameras as if they justify a full replacement.</li>
<li><strong>Built-in waste</strong>: It often makes more profit to sell more devices than to perfect durability or repairability.</li>
</ul>
<p>Those incentives feed a global waste crisis. According to the <em>Global E-waste Monitor</em>, the world generated <strong>62 million tonnes</strong> of electronic waste in 2022, and only about <strong>20 %</strong> of it was formally recycled. That’s billions of dollars in scarce materials sent to landfill or informal recycling while manufacturers push replacement cycles.</p>
<p>This is not innovation. It is churn dressed as progress.</p>
<h2 id="the-software-trap">The Software Trap</h2>
<p>If hardware extracts from the earth, software extracts from our minds. Most mainstream apps are engineered to capture attention and monetize behavior. Infinite scrolling, push notifications, algorithmic ranking of content—these are psychological hooks, not neutral features. Even having a smartphone nearby reduces performance on cognitive tasks. these devices are built and tailored to hijack your mind and thoughts.</p>
<p>Further, behind the engagement lies the real profit: data. Every tap, swipe, pause, and hesitation is tracked, analyzed, and sold. Personal life becomes raw material. This is surveillance capitalism in action.</p>
<h2 id="case-study-2024-snowflake-data-breaches">Case Study: 2024 Snowflake Data Breaches</h2>
<p>In 2024, Snowflake, a major cloud data platform, suffered multiple breaches affecting over 100 of its customers, including prominent organizations. The leaks exposed personal and transactional data, some datasets used for extortion. The cascade of risk showed how vulnerabilities at cloud providers can impact millions often people who never directly interact with those platforms, and the sad thing is, data breaches like this aren&rsquo;t even uncommon.</p>
<p>That your data might be compromised is not theory. It’s built into the chain of services you use: your name, address, habits, purchase history, even medical or ticket data can be swept up by breach after breach.</p>
<h2 id="surveillance-capitalism-and-data-as-commodity">Surveillance Capitalism and Data as Commodity</h2>
<p>This is not an accident. The business model used by many big tech platforms depends on turning attention and human behavior into commodities. The term <em>surveillance capitalism</em> refers to how companies capture and commodify behavioral data to predict and influence future actions.</p>
<p>That commodification creates real harms for ordinary people:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Manipulated behavior</strong>: Ads or political messages become tailored to bypass rational reflection.</li>
<li><strong>Erosion of privacy</strong>: Location history and metadata can reveal where you live, where you travel, or who you meet.</li>
<li><strong>Dynamic pricing &amp; discrimination</strong>: Your inferred financial status or habits might mean you are charged more or offered different deals.</li>
<li><strong>Fraud, identity theft</strong>: When large datasets leak, personal details are on the black market. Scams, phishing, credit fraud follow.</li>
</ul>
<p>In this economy, you are not the customer. You are the product.</p>
<h2 id="why-it-is-needlessly-evil">Why It Is Needlessly Evil</h2>
<p>The worst part is that none of this has to be the norm. Phones could be built to last ten years instead of three. Software could be designed to protect attention and privacy, not break them down. Data could be safeguarded rather than sold.</p>
<p>The point is not that technology must always be harmful. The point is that it doesn’t have to be this harmful. The suffering, the waste, the surveillance. These are choices made because they pay. And those choices leave the rest of us paying the price.</p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Why Women Fear Men and Why Men Misunderstand That Fear</title>
            <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2025/06/why-women-fear-men-and-why-men-misunderstand-that-fear/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2025/06/why-women-fear-men-and-why-men-misunderstand-that-fear/</guid>
            <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A lot of young men get frustrated when women treat them with suspicion or guardedness. They read that as unfair, irrational, or even hostile. I have seen this reaction often: the sense that women are being cold or unjust, that men are being punished for the crimes of others. And yet, beneath the surface, the fear women carry is not irrational. It is rooted in lived reality, in the mental habits women are forced to adopt, and in the way society amplifies certain dangers.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="introduction">Introduction</h2>
<p>A lot of young men get frustrated when women treat them with suspicion or guardedness. They read that as unfair, irrational, or even hostile. I have seen this reaction often: the sense that women are being cold or unjust, that men are being punished for the crimes of others. And yet, beneath the surface, the fear women carry is not irrational. It is rooted in lived reality, in the mental habits women are forced to adopt, and in the way society amplifies certain dangers.</p>
<p>This essay is an attempt to lay that out clearly, to show why women’s caution makes sense, and to suggest a different way for men to respond.</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="part-1-lived-experience">Part 1: Lived Experience</h2>
<p>From a physical standpoint, the difference between men and women is impossible to ignore. The average man is taller, heavier, and stronger than the average woman. In a life-or-death confrontation, that imbalance matters.</p>
<p>For men, it is easy to forget this. We move through the world assuming we could hold our own in a fight, at least against someone roughly our size. Women rarely have that assurance. A woman walking home at night has to calculate her risks differently, even if nothing threatening is happening in the moment.</p>
<p>Think of it like this: if you were walking down a trail and spotted a honey badger, you would instantly recognize it as a potential danger. It does not matter whether that animal is actually aggressive. The point is its capability. Women apply the same logic to men they do not know. Every encounter carries a degree of risk, not because all men are predators, but because enough are, and the cost of misjudging that risk can be catastrophic.</p>
<p>Seen from this angle, women’s caution is not prejudice. It is survival instinct.</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="part-2-mental-habits">Part 2: Mental Habits</h2>
<p>That survival instinct shapes mentality. Women have to stay alert to their surroundings in ways most men never think about: keys in hand when walking through a parking lot, scanning for exits in an unfamiliar room, gauging body language during a conversation. Many simple behaviours and heuristics only developed by men who&rsquo;ve lived in crisis scenarios are the sorts of behaviour women in our society are just generally socialized into developing.</p>
<p>At the same time, cultural norms play a role. Women are often socialized to be more emotionally attuned, to pick up on subtle cues, to notice shifts in tone, to anticipate others’ needs. That sensitivity can heighten fear, because potential threats feel sharper, closer, more personal. Men, by contrast, are often socialized to suppress fear and vulnerability which greatly diminishes their capacity to empathize with the effects that fear women experience in coming to face their vulnerability in the face of a man who may have terrible intentions.</p>
<p>This difference creates a disconnect. Men do not just underestimate women’s fear, they sometimes cannot even imagine it. So when a woman seems cold or distant, it may not be about the man standing in front of her. It is about the thousand calculations she is forced to run just to feel safe.</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="part-3-social-development">Part 3: Social Development</h2>
<p>Finally, there is the world we live in. Social media and the news amplify every horror story: the abduction on a college campus, the violent partner, the stranger who would not take no for an answer. Women see these stories constantly, and each one reinforces the idea that vigilance is non-negotiable.</p>
<p>Ironically, this happens at a time when overall violent crime rates are lower than in the past. But perception matters more than statistics. When people are bombarded with examples of the worst, they naturally adjust their behavior to guard against it. For women, that means being wary of men, sometimes all men, at least until trust is earned.</p>
<p>Men often experience this as rejection. They think: <em>I am not a threat, why am I being treated like one?</em> That frustration is real. But the truth is, it is not personal. Women are not responding to <em>you</em> as an individual. They are responding to the broader reality they inhabit.</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="conclusion-from-anger-to-empathy">Conclusion: From Anger to Empathy</h2>
<p>The problem is not that women are irrational. The problem is that many men take women’s caution as an insult rather than a fact of life. They respond with anger, resentment, or defensiveness. But none of that helps.</p>
<p>The better response is empathy. To recognize that women are navigating a world where they cannot afford to miscalculate. To understand that how you carry yourself, your tone, your body language, your ability to read social cues, matters more than you realize.</p>
<p>If you want to build trust, do not dismiss women’s fear. Respect it. Move in ways that reduce it. Show that you are aware of how your presence affects others.</p>
<p>It is not about being perfect, or handsome, or smooth. Men far less attractive than you have built meaningful relationships because they led with compassion instead of resentment.</p>
<p>The truth is simple, though not easy: empathy is the bridge. It turns suspicion into trust, distance into connection. And that is the only way forward.</p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Contradictions in Holy Texts Are, For The Most Part, Irrelevant</title>
            <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2025/01/contradictions-in-holy-texts-are-for-the-most-part-irrelevant/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2025/01/contradictions-in-holy-texts-are-for-the-most-part-irrelevant/</guid>
            <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-bottom-line&#34;&gt;The Bottom Line&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Bible, and any anthology of holy texts really, are collections of stories from an ancient culture. Stories designed to shape the moral temperance of their people. They do not serve to function as legal codes or IKEA-style instruction manuals. “Do this, don’t do that”; this is not the mode of guidance they were built for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indeed, the characters in these stories sometimes make contradictory claims, and sometimes God himself, as written, seems to say one thing in one book and the opposite in another. But holy texts are stories, filtered through cultural lenses, told and retold by generations who added their own flavor, and further guidance to those stories which would be told to the next. They aren&amp;rsquo;t and were never intended to be read like airtight technical documents.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="the-bottom-line">The Bottom Line</h2>
<p>The Bible, and any anthology of holy texts really, are collections of stories from an ancient culture. Stories designed to shape the moral temperance of their people. They do not serve to function as legal codes or IKEA-style instruction manuals. “Do this, don’t do that”; this is not the mode of guidance they were built for.</p>
<p>Indeed, the characters in these stories sometimes make contradictory claims, and sometimes God himself, as written, seems to say one thing in one book and the opposite in another. But holy texts are stories, filtered through cultural lenses, told and retold by generations who added their own flavor, and further guidance to those stories which would be told to the next. They aren&rsquo;t and were never intended to be read like airtight technical documents.</p>
<p>What looks like contradiction to a modern literalist is usually just evidence of how stories live, shift, and evolve. The real meaning isn’t in the literal words, it’s in the way people heard them, retold them, and used them to shape their lives.</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="a-simple-example">A Simple Example</h2>
<p>Take this contradiction: <em>“God is not the author of confusion”</em> (1 Corinthians 14:33). Seems clear enough. But in Genesis 11:7, at the Tower of Babel, God deliberately confuses humanity’s language. So which is it — author of confusion, or not?</p>
<p>On the surface, it looks like God can’t keep his own story straight. But this is only a problem if you expect the Bible, or any holy text, to behave like a logic puzzle where all the pieces have to fit neatly. Spoiler: it was neither written nor told for that purpose.</p>
<p>Stories aren&rsquo;t so rigid, they don’t need to align like engineering schematics. They’re told by humans, in different times and places, shaped by context, culture, and community. One people group’s “God brings order” can exist alongside another people group’s “God scrambles our plans.” Both can be true in their cultural moment, and neither was intended to be a permanent, contradiction-free rulebook for all eternity.</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="why-contradictions-appear">Why Contradictions Appear</h2>
<p>Contradictions are not divine typos. They are what you get when stories persist through time, passing through the filter of human culture.</p>
<ol>
<li>
<p><strong>Oral storytelling</strong>: Before anything was written down, these stories were shared aloud. Anyone who’s played “broken telephone” knows how that goes. Changes are inevitable in the oral transmission of stories and knowledge.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Cultural lenses</strong>: Different communities shaped the same story according to their values. The nuances of these values are never so easily captured in the literal words of their stories.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Character voices</strong>: Just because someone in a story says “thus saith the Lord” doesn’t mean the statement was written for you as a universal law. Sometimes it’s rhetoric, sometimes it’s culture, sometimes it’s just one character’s perspective.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Transmission problems</strong>: Even if God delivered a perfect revelation, how exactly would a human being, especially a barely literate one, transmit that &ldquo;divine knowledge&rdquo;, something beyond human comprehension, to other humans? Language itself is a filter.</p>
</li>
</ol>
<p>In any situation in which information is conveyed through spoken language, contradictions are inevitable. They’re the fingerprints of humanity on stories that claim to touch the divine.</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="the-failure-of-literalism">The Failure of Literalism</h2>
<p>The real trap here is literalism. Treating holy texts as though they were written to be airtight constitutions or scientific manuals is a modern invention. Ancient cultures weren’t aiming for that.</p>
<p>You don’t read <em>The Iliad</em> to find out whether Zeus actually micromanaged Greek battles, and you don’t read <em>Beowulf</em> as a serious manual on monster-slaying. Yet somehow, when it comes to the Bible, the Quran, or the Vedas, people expect these texts to be perfect transmissions of divine truth, but they&rsquo;re more like man&rsquo;s attempt at conveying it, making that sort of scrutiny flawed even with texts that are &ldquo;divinely inspired.&rdquo;</p>
<p>That approach doesn’t just miss the point, it makes the text unreadable. These are stories. Their job is to inspire, to warn, to shape identity, and to anchor communities. They were never meant to hold up to courtroom-style cross-examination.</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="the-limits-of-human-understanding">The Limits of Human Understanding</h2>
<p>Even if you accept divine revelation as real, that doesn’t mean contradictions vanish. Because the second revelation hits human ears, it’s already compromised. Not out of malice, just because the human mind cannot repackage the pure, the infinite, the divine into sentences.</p>
<p>Think of it like this: try explaining the concept of a supermarket to an ant. The ant knows “food” and maybe “food storage.” But how do you explain exchange, money, cash registers, and legal tender? You can’t.</p>
<p>Now scale that up. The distance between human understanding and divine reality is infinitely wider than the gap between an ant and a human. So if someone claims they’ve perfectly conveyed God’s eternal truth into a neat paragraph? Sorry, not possible.</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="why-contradictions-do-not-matter">Why Contradictions Do Not Matter</h2>
<p>So why don’t contradictions matter? Because for the vast majority of people, the value of holy texts isn&rsquo;t in their factual precision. Their value and power lies in their ability to inspire reflection, guide communities, instill purpose, help people wrestle with the big questions, and ground their sense of self somewhere in the universe.</p>
<p>Critics who point to contradictions often miss this. They assume religion collapses if the text isn’t flawless. But most religious life has never depended on flawless texts. It has depended on stories reshaped through tradition, culture, and practice.</p>
<p>Holy texts endure not because every line agrees, but because the stories still work. They still guide, still inspire, still comfort, still provoke, still anchor communities across generations.</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h2>
<p>Contradictions in holy texts aren’t flaws, they’re cultural artifacts. They show us how culture shapes meaning and how humans struggle to express the inexpressible.</p>
<p>Whether it’s the Bible, the Quran, the Vedas, or any other sacred writing, contradictions don’t erase their importance. They remind us that these are human-told stories reaching toward something bigger, not instruction manuals demanding literal precision.</p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
